Guide to the Walter Eugene Johnston papers, 1980-1982
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Walter Eugene Johnston papers 1980-1982
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Johnston, Walter Eugene
20 linear feet Extent: Approx. 19,300 Items
Member of the U.S. House of Representatives from North Carolina; served on the House Budget and Labor and Education Committees. The papers of Walter Eugene Johnston, III, U.S. Representative from the 6th District of North Carolina, span the years 1980 to 1982, the time during which he served the 97th Congress. The collection consists of correspondence, clippings, and committee files, with subjects including current legislation, congressional caucuses, North Carolina public events, and regulatory reform. Committee files cover topics including budgets, banking, finance, urban affairs, education and labor, bills, health and safety, education, labor, energy, commerce, tax, and trade.
RL.00640
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Walter Eugene Johnston papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift and purchase in 1982.
Collection Overview
The papers of Walter Eugene Johnston, III, U.S. Representative from the 6th District of North Carolina, span the years 1980 to 1982, the time during which he served the 97th Congress. The collection consists of correspondence, clippings, and committee files, with subjects including current legislation, congressional caucuses, North Carolina public events, and regulatory reform. Committee files cover topics including budgets, banking, finance, urban affairs, education and labor, bills, health and safety, education, labor, energy, commerce, tax, and trade.
Subject Headings
Johnston, Walter Eugene; United States. Congress. House; Legislators -- North Carolina; United States -- Politics and government -- 1977-1981
Contents of the Collection
- Correspondence Files, 1980 Nov.-1982 Dec., (20 boxes)
  - 1980 Nov.-1981 Feb. (Box 1)
  - 1981 Feb.-Mar. (Box 2)
  - 1981 Mar.-April (Box 3)
  - 1981 April-May (Box 4)
  - 1981 May-Sep. (Box 5)
  - 1981 Sep.-Oct. (Box 6)
  - 1981 Oct.-Nov. (Box 7)
  - 1981 Nov.-Dec. (Box 8)
  - 1981 Dec.-1982 Jan. (Box 9)
  - 1982 Jan.-Feb. (Box 10)
  - 1982 Feb. (Box 11)
  - 1982 March (Box 12)
  - 1982 March-April (Box 13)
  - 1982 April (Box 14)
  - 1982 April-May (Box 15)
  - 1982 April-June (Box 16)
  - 1982 June-July (Box 17)
  - 1982 July-Aug. (Box 18)
  - 1982 Aug.-Sep. (Box 19)
  - 1982 Sep.-Dec. (Box 20)
- Subject Files, 1980-1982, (4 boxes)
  - Biography (Box 21)
  - Legislative profile (Box 21)
  - Passport (Box 21)
  - Press releases (Box 21)
  - Ratings (Box 21)
  - Legislation (Box 22)
  - American Textile Machinery Association (Box 23)
  - Congressional Rural Caucus (Box 23)
  - Congressional Textile Caucus (Box 23)
  - Furniture Mfrs. Assoc. Position Papers (Box 23)
  - General correspondence (Box 23)
  - North Carolina Republican Club of Washington (Box 23)
  - North Carolina Shakespeare Festival (Box 23)
  - North Carolina transportation, highway construction (Box 23)
  - Pig Bowl (Box 23)
  - Radial keratotomy (Box 23)
  - Radial Keratotomy (Box 24)
  - Regulatory reform (Box 24)
  - Sunbelt Caucus (Box 24)
- Clippings, 1980 Nov.-1982 Nov., (4 boxes)
  Series scope/content note
  - 1980 Nov.-1981 Aug. (Box 25)
  - 1981 Sep.-1982 May (Box 26)
  - 1982 May-Oct. (Box 27)
  - 1982 Oct.-Nov. (Box 28)
  - Other dates (Box 28)
- Committee Files, 1980-1982, (14 boxes)
  Committees with which Walter E. Johnston was affiliated, or issues in which he had had an interest.
  - Banking, finance, and urban affairs (Box 29)
  - Budget (Box 29)
  - Budget (Box 30)
  - Budget (Box 31)
  - Education and labor (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous information (Box 32)
    - Bills (Box 32)
    - Black lung information (Box 33)
    - Committee proceedings (Box 33)
    - Cotton Dust Standard (Box 33)
    - Davis-Bacon Act (Box 34)
    - E.R.I.S.A. information (Box 34)
    - Farm Labor Contractor Registration Act (Box 34)
    - F.E.C.A. information (Box 34)
    - FLSA (Box 35)
    - Government Printing Office (Box 35)
    - Health and Safety (Box 35)
    - Labor information (Box 36)
    - Labor-management relations (Box 36)
    - Labor-management, Service Contract Act (Box 36)
    - Labor standards (Box 37)
    - M.S.H.A. (Box 37)
    - N.I.O.S.H. (Box 37)
    - Occupational safety (Box 37)
    - Right to Work letter to the President (Box 37)
    - O.S.H.A. information (Box 38)
    - O.S.H.A. Consultation program in N.C. (Box 38)
  - Energy and commerce (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous information (Box 39)
    - Legislation (Box 39)
    - Communications information (Box 39)
    - Communications, H.R.5158 (Box 40)
    - Communications, AT&T (Box 40)
    - Energy, information (Box 40)
    - Energy, Alaskan pipeline (Box 40)
    - Energy, Dept. of Energy (Box 40)
    - Energy, electric utilities (Box 41)
    - Energy, natural Gas (Box 41)
    - Energy, nuclear (Box 41)
    - Energy, oil (Box 41)
  - Ways and means (Box 42)
    - Administration's social services block grant (Box 42)
    - Aging, legislative information (Box 42)
    - Information (Box 42)
    - Social Security, administration and HHS proposal (Box 42)
    - Social Security information (Box 42)
    - Tax, President Reagan's proposals (Box 42)
    - Trade (Box 42)
    - Urban enterprise zone legislation (Box 42)
    - Legislation (Box 43)
    - Tax information (Box 44)